<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/Security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/Security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recover database encrypted modules code with dbatools</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/09/22/Recover-database-encrypted-modules-code-with-dbatools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/09/22/Recover-database-encrypted-modules-code-with-dbatools/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article was initially posted on &lt;a href="https://www.sqlservercentral.com/articles/recover-database-encrypted-modules-code-with-dbatools"

 
 target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"
>
 SQLServerCentral
&lt;/a>
 @ 2020-08-18.
It was interesting some comments I read about it, mainly why people still use &lt;code>WITH ENCRYPTION&lt;/code> when it&amp;rsquo;s simple to overcome this when we have the right permissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SQL Server offers an option to encrypt the code of your modules when using the &lt;code>WITH ENCRYPTION&lt;/code> syntax.
This allows to hide/obfuscate the modules&amp;rsquo; code and thus keep away from prying eyes.
It&amp;rsquo;s often used to protect business rules since it allows you to protect some intellectual property.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When one of your DBA colleagues leaves the company, what is your checklist?</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/09/03/When-one-of-your-DBA-colleagues-leaves-the-company-what-is-your-checklist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/09/03/When-one-of-your-DBA-colleagues-leaves-the-company-what-is-your-checklist/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whether it’s in our personal lives or the professional one, we do have checklists for certain tasks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the professional level, it can be purely technical like SQL Server installation, configuration or even uninstall, but they can also be not so technical like when a colleague join the team and someone needs to request permissions to access the company&amp;rsquo;s tools (such as ticketing/incidents/VPN/etc).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-about-when-a-colleague-leaves-the-company">What about when a colleague leaves the company?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What is your checklist for this situation?
At first, and the most obvious is to &amp;ldquo;rollback&amp;rdquo; the things done when that person joined the company. For instance:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generate SQL Server Role Member Reports using dbatools and ImportExcel PowerShell modules</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/07/31/Generate-SQL-Server-Role-Member-Reports-using-dbatools-and-ImportExcel-PowerShell-modules/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/07/31/Generate-SQL-Server-Role-Member-Reports-using-dbatools-and-ImportExcel-PowerShell-modules/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This was initial posted on &lt;a href="https://www.sqlservercentral.com/articles/generate-role-member-reports-using-dbatools-and-the-importexcel-powershell-modules"

 
 target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"
>
 SQL Server Central articles
&lt;/a>
.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As one of dbatools&amp;rsquo; first members, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for years and it&amp;rsquo;s really my goto tool. This task was no different!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s tip and trick using &lt;a href="https://dbatools.io"

 
 target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"
>
 dbatools
&lt;/a>
 is about generating an Excel workbook that contains lists of SQL Server roles and its members.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-usefulness-of-these-reports">The Usefulness of these Reports&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These reports are especially useful when performing tech-refreshes (migrating from an old version to a newer one) and you want to do some housekeeping. For example, finding logins that should be part of a role and they are not. Once you know there are problems, you decided to do a double-check on the whole list.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change Outlook sender mailbox with PowerShell - A workaround</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/02/12/Change-Outlook-sender-mailbox-with-PowerShell-A-workaround/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/02/12/Change-Outlook-sender-mailbox-with-PowerShell-A-workaround/</guid><description>&lt;p>The idea of this blog post, like many others I write, is to document a workaround solution to my problem. Hopefully I can also help someone that may be looking for the solution for this problem and stumbles accidentally (or not) on my blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="scenario">Scenario&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was helping a colleague automating the creation of emails using Microsoft Outlook using PowerShell. The following are configurable options (these will be the parameters of the script):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Temporarily enable TLS 1.0/1.1? - Be sure you check this keys</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/02/04/Temporarily-enable-TLS-1.0/1.1-Be-sure-you-check-this-keys/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/02/04/Temporarily-enable-TLS-1.0/1.1-Be-sure-you-check-this-keys/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are some actions that we know that will have to be repeated from time to time, but the surprise comes when it’s time to do so and the process that used to work does not work anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a short post to document a slight change that I had to do to achieve the same final result as the first time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="long-story-short">Long story short&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A client needed to run a setup to install an application. This setup uses a utility called &lt;code>minisql.exe&lt;/code> to test database connection. The problem is that this utility only works with TLS 1.0/1.1 and, on our systems, we only have TLS 1.2 enabled.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>