<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Share on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/share/</link><description>Recent content in Share on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/share/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SQL Server Operations Studio and VSCode: The wrong default datetimeoffset format</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/09/12/SQL-Server-Operations-Studio-and-VSCode-The-wrong-default-datetimeoffset-format/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/09/12/SQL-Server-Operations-Studio-and-VSCode-The-wrong-default-datetimeoffset-format/</guid><description>This post is to answer the question: &amp;ldquo;You are used to seeing in the format of yyyy-MM-dd right?&amp;rdquo; that I have raised on my blog post Don’t cutoff yourself with dates in T-SQL – Did you know… .
As you could see from that blog post, my screen shots were from VSCode and in this case using mssql extension, but this happens also on SQL Server Operations Studio .
&amp;ldquo;But why are my datetimeoffset values on VSCode being showed in that format?</description></item><item><title>Learn, Evolve and Giving Back - TSQL Tuesday 102</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/05/08/Learn-Evolve-and-Giving-Back-TSQL-Tuesday-102/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/05/08/Learn-Evolve-and-Giving-Back-TSQL-Tuesday-102/</guid><description>This month’s T-SQL Tuesday is brought to us by Riley Major‏ ( b | t ) and he encourage us to talk about how we are helping by giving back to our community.
This is the 102nd edition of TSQL2sDay - an Adam Machanic’s ( b | t ) brainchild.
&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s go back for a moment:&amp;rdquo; I have heard about SQL Server the first time back in 2003 when I was on the high school and I had a database class.</description></item><item><title>TSQL Tuesday 96: Folks Who Have Made a Difference</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/11/14/TSQL-Tuesday-96-Folks-Who-Have-Made-a-Difference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/11/14/TSQL-Tuesday-96-Folks-Who-Have-Made-a-Difference/</guid><description>This month’s T-SQL Tuesday is brought to us by Ewald Cress ( blog | twitter ) and is all about &amp;ldquo;folks who have made a difference&amp;rdquo; in our careers.
Thank you, Ewald! This is a great topic!
Here is my short list Paulo Silva ( in ) He was my first boss in the IT world! I was his apprentice when I started my internship. He was going to move to a manager position and I had to continue his work.</description></item><item><title>PowerShell Modules Central - Share with community - What PowerShell modules are you using?</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/09/19/PowerShell-Modules-Central-Share-with-community-What-PowerShell-modules-are-you-using/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/09/19/PowerShell-Modules-Central-Share-with-community-What-PowerShell-modules-are-you-using/</guid><description>Like the blog post title states this is all about sharing with others! My idea is to share with the community which PowerShell modules you are using.
Let me introduce to you the PowerShell Modules Central PowerShellModulesCentral is a GitHub repository that was founded as a central hub to a list of PowerShell modules that people know/use. Each module has a file describing its name, basic information about the module, as well as one or more blog posts/videos from people that have written about or used them.</description></item></channel></rss>