<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Permissions on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/Permissions/</link><description>Recent content in Permissions on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/Permissions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When one of your DBA colleagues leaves the company, what is your checklist?</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/09/03/When-one-of-your-DBA-colleagues-leaves-the-company-what-is-your-checklist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/09/03/When-one-of-your-DBA-colleagues-leaves-the-company-what-is-your-checklist/</guid><description>Whether it’s in our personal lives or the professional one, we do have checklists for certain tasks.
On the professional level, it can be purely technical like SQL Server installation, configuration or even uninstall, but they can also be not so technical like when a colleague join the team and someone needs to request permissions to access the company&amp;rsquo;s tools (such as ticketing/incidents/VPN/etc).
What about when a colleague leaves the company?</description></item><item><title>Generate SQL Server Role Member Reports using dbatools and ImportExcel PowerShell modules</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/07/31/Generate-SQL-Server-Role-Member-Reports-using-dbatools-and-ImportExcel-PowerShell-modules/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/07/31/Generate-SQL-Server-Role-Member-Reports-using-dbatools-and-ImportExcel-PowerShell-modules/</guid><description>This was initial posted on SQL Server Central articles .
As one of dbatools&amp;rsquo; first members, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for years and it&amp;rsquo;s really my goto tool. This task was no different!
Today&amp;rsquo;s tip and trick using dbatools is about generating an Excel workbook that contains lists of SQL Server roles and its members.
The Usefulness of these Reports These reports are especially useful when performing tech-refreshes (migrating from an old version to a newer one) and you want to do some housekeeping.</description></item><item><title>Replicate permissions to new Login/User with dbatools</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/05/28/Replicate-permissions-to-new-Login/User-with-dbatools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/05/28/Replicate-permissions-to-new-Login/User-with-dbatools/</guid><description>Continuing to share tips and tricks using dbatools like the Refresh databases that belongs to availability group using dbatools posted a few days ago, today I will share a way to export the permissions of a login/user at instance/database level and apply them to a new login/user.
The typical request Client: &amp;ldquo;We have a new colleague, can you please grant them the exact same permissions I have?!&amp;rdquo;
A quick note/suggestion that may help minimize your work: If we are talking about a Windows Login, please suggest the use of AD groups to help you (so that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do this process) and also them (they don&amp;rsquo;t need to make this request).</description></item></channel></rss>