<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BestPractices on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/BestPractices/</link><description>Recent content in BestPractices on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/BestPractices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When one of your DBA colleagues leaves the company, what is your checklist?</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/09/03/When-one-of-your-DBA-colleagues-leaves-the-company-what-is-your-checklist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/09/03/When-one-of-your-DBA-colleagues-leaves-the-company-what-is-your-checklist/</guid><description>Whether it’s in our personal lives or the professional one, we do have checklists for certain tasks.
On the professional level, it can be purely technical like SQL Server installation, configuration or even uninstall, but they can also be not so technical like when a colleague join the team and someone needs to request permissions to access the company&amp;rsquo;s tools (such as ticketing/incidents/VPN/etc).
What about when a colleague leaves the company?</description></item><item><title>Someone is not following the best practices - dbatools and Pester don't lie!</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/09/12/Someone-is-not-following-the-best-practices-dbatools-and-Pester-dont-lie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/09/12/Someone-is-not-following-the-best-practices-dbatools-and-Pester-dont-lie/</guid><description>This month’s T-SQL Tuesday is brought to us by my good friend Rob Sewell ( b | t ). Together “Let’s get all Posh – What are you going to automate today?”
I have written some blog posts on how I use PowerShell to automate mundane tasks or some other more complex scenarios like: Find and fix SQL Server databases with empty owner property using dbatools PowerShell module or Have you backed up your SQL Logins today?</description></item></channel></rss>