<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TSQL2sDay on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/TSQL2sDay/</link><description>Recent content in TSQL2sDay on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/TSQL2sDay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TSQL Tuesday 127 - Non SQL Tips and Tricks - Windows</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/06/09/TSQL-Tuesday-127-Non-SQL-Tips-and-Tricks-Windows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2020/06/09/TSQL-Tuesday-127-Non-SQL-Tips-and-Tricks-Windows/</guid><description>This month’s (#127) T-SQL Tuesday is brought by B | T) and he asked about Non SQL Tips and tricks. As a Windows user I know there are lots of shortcuts and small hacks, that I love, which make my life much easier! Here is my small contribution:
Windows tips &amp;amp; tricks and shortcuts Open &amp;ldquo;Add or Remove programs&amp;rdquo; A way to open the &amp;ldquo;Add or Remove programs&amp;rdquo; menu quicker, you can SHIFT + DEL on the shortcut (example: Docker Desktop) on desktop and the prompt popup will have there a link to this option.</description></item><item><title>Triggers: The hidden logic that will strike back - TSQL Tuesday #106</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/09/11/Triggers-The-hidden-logic-that-will-strike-back-TSQL-Tuesday-#106/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/09/11/Triggers-The-hidden-logic-that-will-strike-back-TSQL-Tuesday-#106/</guid><description>This month’s T-SQL Tuesday is brought by Steve Jones (b | t) and he wants to know if triggers causes headaches or happiness to us.
This is the 106nd edition of TSQL2sDay - an Adam Machanic (b | t) brainchild.
Triggers are those kind of database objects that sometimes are the best bet but most of the times they will strike back.
&amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; - You may ask. From my experience triggers are objects that we &amp;ldquo;tend&amp;rdquo; to forget are there, and only when we hit a problem and, sometimes, after digging into the problem we end by saying something like</description></item><item><title>Learn, Evolve and Giving Back - TSQL Tuesday #102</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/05/08/Learn-Evolve-and-Giving-Back-TSQL-Tuesday-#102/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/05/08/Learn-Evolve-and-Giving-Back-TSQL-Tuesday-#102/</guid><description>This month’s T-SQL Tuesday is brought to us by Riley Major‏ (b | t) and he encourage us to talk about how we are helping by giving back to our community.
This is the 102nd edition of TSQL2sDay - an Adam Machanic’s (b | t) brainchild.
Let&amp;rsquo;s go back for a moment: I have heard about SQL Server the first time back in 2003 when I was on the high school and I had a database class.</description></item><item><title>TSQL Tuesday #96: Folks Who Have Made a Difference</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/11/14/TSQL-Tuesday-#96-Folks-Who-Have-Made-a-Difference/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/11/14/TSQL-Tuesday-#96-Folks-Who-Have-Made-a-Difference/</guid><description>blog | twitter) and is all about &amp;ldquo;folks who have made a difference&amp;rdquo; in our careers.
Thank you, Ewald! This is a great topic!
Here is my short list: Paulo Silva (in) He was my first boss in the IT world! I was his apprentice when I started my internship. He was going to move to a manager position and I had to continue his work. He was responsible for the beginning of my career with SQL Server 2000 and VB6.</description></item></channel></rss>