<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>syndicate on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/syndicate/</link><description>Recent content in syndicate on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 09:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/syndicate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Search for queries with Query Store GUI</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2024/01/29/Search-for-queries-with-Query-Store-GUI/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2024/01/29/Search-for-queries-with-Query-Store-GUI/</guid><description>Hey folks, long time no write!
Today I want to bring a tip that I use every week but I found that most SSMS users are unaware it exists.
I can understand why! At the moment this isn&amp;rsquo;t the most obvious and user-friendly option. However, it can and hopefully it will improve in the future.
&amp;ldquo;But&amp;hellip;What is it?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m talking about using the Query Store GUI to search for some portion of text used in a T-SQL query and, with that, find a query that you want to analyze within it.</description></item><item><title>dbatools - Exceptions</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2022/06/07/dbatools-Exceptions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2022/06/07/dbatools-Exceptions/</guid><description>Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t like a good red and verbose exception?
At PowerShell community we often call it a &amp;ldquo;sea of red&amp;rdquo; which we found as something that can be intimidating. The bigger the error message the more problematic it is? :-)
We don&amp;rsquo;t think so! That&amp;rsquo;s why we, within dbatools project, try to keep the output of the exceptions more user friendly and try to give the direct error message to you.</description></item><item><title>dbatools - rich datatypes</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2022/06/02/dbatools-rich-datatypes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2022/06/02/dbatools-rich-datatypes/</guid><description>Some datatypes can be shown in so many different forms (think measurament units, dates with short/long forms, or regional settings) that can be difficult to have a standard.
What should we show? Sizes should be always in bytes? It will be easier for you to interpret 1610612736 bytes or 1.50 GB?
That&amp;rsquo;s why we have created some rich datatypes like, DbaTime, DbaDate, DbaDatetime, DbaTimeSpan, PrettyTimeSpan or DbaSize to make it easier to read and be more consistent acrross multiple commands.</description></item></channel></rss>