<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Power BI on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/Power-BI/</link><description>Recent content in Power BI on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/Power-BI/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>dbachecks - A different approach for an in-progress and incremental validation</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/02/22/dbachecks-A-different-approach-for-an-in-progress-and-incremental-validation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/02/22/dbachecks-A-different-approach-for-an-in-progress-and-incremental-validation/</guid><description>dbachecks is a new PowerShell module from the SQL Server Community! For more information, read introducing dbachecks.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know dbachecks, we have released a good amount of blog posts that will help you: Announcing dbachecks – Configurable PowerShell Validation For Your SQL Instances by Rob Sewell introducing dbachecks - a new module from the dbatools team! by Chrissy LeMaire install dbachecks by Chrissy LeMaire dbachecks commands by Chrissy LeMaire dbachecks – Using Power BI dashboards to analyse results by Cláudio Silva My wrapper for dbachecks by Tony Wilhelm Checking backups with dbachecks by Jess Promfret dbachecks please!</description></item><item><title>dbachecks - Using Power BI dashboards to analyse results</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/02/22/dbachecks-Using-Power-BI-dashboards-to-analyse-results/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/02/22/dbachecks-Using-Power-BI-dashboards-to-analyse-results/</guid><description>For the last couple of months, members of the dbatools team have been working on a new PowerShell module called dbachecks. This open source PowerShell module will enable you to validate your SQL Instances. Today it is released for you all to start to use 🙂
Here you can find a list of the blog posts made available today: Announcing dbachecks – Configurable PowerShell Validation For Your SQL Instances by Rob Sewell introducing dbachecks - a new module from the dbatools team!</description></item></channel></rss>