<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TSQL on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/TSQL/</link><description>Recent content in TSQL on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/TSQL/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What happens when we drop a column on a SQL Server table? Where's my space?</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2024/05/29/What-happens-when-we-drop-a-column-on-a-SQL-Server-table-Wheres-my-space/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2024/05/29/What-happens-when-we-drop-a-column-on-a-SQL-Server-table-Wheres-my-space/</guid><description>This article was initially posted on SQLServerCentral @ 2024-04-26.
Short answer: The column is marked as &amp;lsquo;deleted&amp;rsquo; and will stop being visible/usable.
But, most importantly - The record/table size will remain unchanged.
A metadata operation Dropping a column is a metadata/logical operation, not a physical one. This means that the data isn&amp;rsquo;t removed/overwritten by this action. As Paul Randal mentions here :
&amp;ldquo;the cost of that will be deferred for the inserters and not for the deleters&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Check Azure SQL DB Space Used</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2024/05/02/Check-Azure-SQL-DB-Space-Used/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2024/05/02/Check-Azure-SQL-DB-Space-Used/</guid><description>A couple of days ago I was doing some cleaning on some Azure SQL DBs and shrinking some files to lower the bill.
To check my progress I needed to check the size before/after the task in an easy way for multiple Azure SQL DBs.
Check Azure SQL DB storage space for 1 database If you need to check the storage space being used by 1 Azure SQL DB, that is as easy as jumping on the portal, select the desired database and you can find the information in the Overview.</description></item><item><title>Using Common Table Expression (CTE) - Did you know...</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/11/30/Using-Common-Table-Expression-CTE-Did-you-know.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2017/11/30/Using-Common-Table-Expression-CTE-Did-you-know.../</guid><description>Today I will write just a short blog post to do a quick reminder!
I still hear a lot of people suggesting CTEs because they think it works like a temporary table (you populate the table and then it can be/is reutilized).
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t!
From de documentation :
Specifies a temporary named result set, known as a common table expression (CTE).
Maybe they are focusing on the &amp;ldquo;temporary&amp;rdquo; word.
Using the CTE two times will perform two different executions!</description></item></channel></rss>