<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSMS on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/SSMS/</link><description>Recent content in SSMS on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/SSMS/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SSMS GUI not working? Try to use T-SQL!</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2019/03/29/SSMS-GUI-not-working-Try-to-use-T-SQL/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2019/03/29/SSMS-GUI-not-working-Try-to-use-T-SQL/</guid><description>One of the good things, when we have new clients, is that sometimes they have needs that you never heard before. This does not necessarily mean that they are complex. As a matter of fact, they can be really simple..now the question is..are they doable? :-)
From my experience, this can happen mainly because one of two reasons, they have some very specific need, or because the way the application is built will make you work with features that you haven&amp;rsquo;t played yet.</description></item><item><title>Did you know...you can change the default file encoding for new query on SSMS?</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/06/05/Did-you-know...you-can-change-the-default-file-encoding-for-new-query-on-SSMS/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/06/05/Did-you-know...you-can-change-the-default-file-encoding-for-new-query-on-SSMS/</guid><description>If you have been reading my last blog posts, you know that I’m currently working on a SQL code migration from Firebird to SQL Server.
The client provided the scripts with all modules (Stored Procedures, functions, etc) and the steps I&amp;rsquo;m following (roughly speaking) for converting are:
So&amp;hellip;what is happening? On this process, the unicode characters are replaced by some symbols.
How to solve? We can change the default file encoding in order to be the one we want in the first place.</description></item></channel></rss>