<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dbachecks on Cláudio Silva's Blog</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/dbachecks/</link><description>Recent content in dbachecks on Cláudio Silva's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claudioessilva.eu/tags/dbachecks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I will be speaking @ SQLSaturday 795 Porto</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/09/05/I-will-be-speaking-@-SQLSaturday-795-Porto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/09/05/I-will-be-speaking-@-SQLSaturday-795-Porto/</guid><description>On 29th September we will have SQL Saturday Porto and I’m proud to announce that I will be speaking!
I will be speaking about dbachecks PowerShell module - dbachecks - Checking SQL Server environments with PowerShell .
The event will be held at ISEP, Rua Dr. António Bernardino de Almeida, 431, 4249-015 Porto, Portugal and you can see the full schedule here .
Register , it&amp;rsquo;s free!
Hope to see you in Porto!</description></item><item><title>I will be speaking @ Tuga IT 2018</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/07/06/I-will-be-speaking-@-Tuga-IT-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/07/06/I-will-be-speaking-@-Tuga-IT-2018/</guid><description>Starting on 19th of July and during 3 days the Tuga IT 2018 Summer Edition will be happening in Lisbon!
This edition will have:
4 full-day workshops 38 breakout sessions (1 hour) 5 deep dive sessions (2 hours) That is over 72 hours of content delivered by 44 awesome speakers, many of them recognized industry experts.
You can see the full schedule here . This edition will have sessions about: Cloud, Data Platform, Development, Integration, IOT, Office, PowerShell and Security.</description></item><item><title>Learn, Evolve and Giving Back - TSQL Tuesday 102</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/05/08/Learn-Evolve-and-Giving-Back-TSQL-Tuesday-102/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/05/08/Learn-Evolve-and-Giving-Back-TSQL-Tuesday-102/</guid><description>This month’s T-SQL Tuesday is brought to us by Riley Major‏ ( b | t ) and he encourage us to talk about how we are helping by giving back to our community.
This is the 102nd edition of TSQL2sDay - an Adam Machanic’s ( b | t ) brainchild.
&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s go back for a moment:&amp;rdquo; I have heard about SQL Server the first time back in 2003 when I was on the high school and I had a database class.</description></item><item><title>dbachecks - Going parallel - Cut off your execution times</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/04/26/dbachecks-Going-parallel-Cut-off-your-execution-times/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/04/26/dbachecks-Going-parallel-Cut-off-your-execution-times/</guid><description>On one of the last clients I have worked, I have implemented dbachecks in order to get the state of art and know how cool or bad the environments are before start knocking down the bad practices.
This client has seven different environments with more than 100 instances and more than 2000 databases.
Serial execution A non-parallel execution (single session) took more than 2 hours. This is not a big problem when we run it out of hours and we don&amp;rsquo;t want/need to be looking or waiting for it to finish.</description></item><item><title>dbachecks - Setting temporary configuration values</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/04/24/dbachecks-Setting-temporary-configuration-values/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/04/24/dbachecks-Setting-temporary-configuration-values/</guid><description>dbachecks has seen the light about two months ago. As I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post, the module counts with more than 2600 downloads just from the PowerShell gallery . The module has about 110 configurable checks that make our live easier!
Today I will write about an option that I think users still do not realize that exists.
The default dbachecks works with the values previously saved (for that we use Set-DbcConfig).</description></item><item><title>dbachecks - A different approach for an in-progress and incremental validation</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/02/22/dbachecks-A-different-approach-for-an-in-progress-and-incremental-validation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/02/22/dbachecks-A-different-approach-for-an-in-progress-and-incremental-validation/</guid><description>dbachecks is a new PowerShell module from the SQL Server Community! For more information, read introducing dbachecks .
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know dbachecks, we have released a good amount of blog posts that will help you: Announcing dbachecks – Configurable PowerShell Validation For Your SQL Instances by Rob Sewell introducing dbachecks - a new module from the dbatools team! by Chrissy LeMaire install dbachecks by Chrissy LeMaire dbachecks commands by Chrissy LeMaire dbachecks – Using Power BI dashboards to analyse results by Cláudio Silva My wrapper for dbachecks by Tony Wilhelm Checking backups with dbachecks by Jess Promfret dbachecks please!</description></item><item><title>dbachecks - Using Power BI dashboards to analyse results</title><link>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/02/22/dbachecks-Using-Power-BI-dashboards-to-analyse-results/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claudioessilva.eu/2018/02/22/dbachecks-Using-Power-BI-dashboards-to-analyse-results/</guid><description>For the last couple of months, members of the dbatools team have been working on a new PowerShell module called dbachecks. This open source PowerShell module will enable you to validate your SQL Instances. Today it is released for you all to start to use 🙂
dbachecks launch - the blog posts series Here you can find a list of the blog posts made available today:
Announcing dbachecks – Configurable PowerShell Validation For Your SQL Instances by Rob Sewell introducing dbachecks - a new module from the dbatools team!</description></item></channel></rss>